Register to The Richard Donovan Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, 1913-1970; Series I; 4 Boxes
  - Yaddo papers, I.E
    - From E. Ames to Quincy Porter, 1958 Mar. 31; 1 typed letters signed. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - From E. Ames to Ulysses Kay, 1968; 2 typed letters (carbon). (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings about Yaddo (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Miscellaneous typescripts concerning Yaddo (Constitution, programs, etc.)
  - Yale papers, I.F
    - Yale School of Music (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Miscellaneous typescripts.
    - Newspaper clippings about Yale (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - New Haven Symphony, I.G
    - From R.J. Reich to Donovan, 1950; 2 postcards. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - From Frank Sheridan to Donovan, 1949; 2 typed letters signed. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - From Samuel Galpin to Donovan, 1949 Mar. 30; 1 autograph letters signed. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - From Donovan to Yale Daily News, 1930 Dec. 15; 1 typed letter (carbon). (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Gordon Armstrong, 1949 May 11; 1 typed letter (carbon). (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - John H. Jackson, 1950 Dec. 11; 1 typed letter (carbon). (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous memos, lists of orchestral pieces, publicity folders, etc. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Photographs, 1921-1965; Series II; 1 Box
  Photographs are arranged as follows: Donovan alone, Donovan family group pictures including Donovan, other people, with unidentified pictures coming at the end. These photos consist of individuals such as Elizabeth Ames (director of Yaddo festivals), Max Polikoff, Henry Cowell, and includes a signed postcard photo of Charles Widor.
  - Donovan, Richard, undated (early); 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Donovan, Richard, undated (middle); 2 items. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Donovan, Richard, 1956; 4 items. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Donovan, Richard, 1964; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Donovan and son, undated; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Grace Donovan and son; son alone, undated; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Donovan conducting New Haven Symphony and School of Music group, undated (195-?); 6 items. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Group pictures (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Donovan and girl's choir, undated (early); 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Burton, Margaret Crofts, Max Pollikoff, Hinrichsen, Donovan, 1964; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Donovan and Max Pollikoff, 1964; 2 items. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Donovan and Avery Claflin, 1965; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Donovan and Elizabeth Ames, 1965; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Donovan, Henry Gowell, Elizabeth Ames, Avery Claflin, 1965; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Wyner, Nancy Braverman, 1955; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Wyner, Yehudi, 1955; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Widor, Charles Marie, 1921; signed postcard. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - St. Peters Cathedral in Rome, inside, 1951; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified child, Ann, 1950; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified child, Joanna, 1950; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified child, Kit, 1950; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Arbald, Milton, 1958; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Programs, 1918-1969; Series III; 4 Boxes
  This collection of programs is divided into 3 main categories: Those on which Donovan's works were performed, those for which Donovan served as conductor or performer, those which Donovan attended.
  Also included are programs on which Grace Donovan (Mrs.) sang, and New Haven Symphony programs during the time Donovan was associate conductor but for which he did not conduct.
  - Donovan's works performed, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Donovan's works performed, 1930-1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Donovan's works performed, 1940-1945 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Donovan's works performed, 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Donovan's works performed, 1950-1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Donovan's works performed, 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Grace Donovan as performer (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Donovan as conductor or performer, 1918-1939 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Donovan as conductor or performer, 1940-1949 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Donovan as conductor or performer, 1950-1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - New Haven Symphony programs, 1940-1949 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Donovan conductor but not of these programs.
  - Programs Donovan attended, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Programs Donovan attended, 1919-1929 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Programs Donovan attended, 1930-1939 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Programs Donovan attended, 1940-1949 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Programs Donovan attended, 1950-1965 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Clippings, 19--; Series IV; 3 Boxes
  The clippings found in this section deal with several areas:
  Articles about Donovan as composer/conductor.
  Reviews of Donovan's works (arranged alphabetically by the name of the work).
  Articles which Donovan collected concerning composers (Bach-Wagner) arranged alphabetically.
  Articles which Donovan collected covering periods of music.
  Miscellaneous articles (on instruments, book reviews, etc.)
  - Clippings concerning Donovan, 32 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Reviews of Donovan's works, 18 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Design for radio; Elizabethan Lyrics; Fantasy on American folk ballads; miscellaneous ballads and songs.
  - Reviews of Donovan's works, 19 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Music for six; New England Chronicle; Organ works.
  - Reviews of Donovan's works, 22 items. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Quartet for woodwinds; Ricercare; Serenade; Soundings; Suite no. 2 for piano.
  - Reviews of Donovan's works, 18 items. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Suite for oboe and string orchestra; Woodnotes.
  - Reviews of Donovan's works, 10 items. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Miscellaneous mixture.
  - Articles about Bach and Händel (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Articles about Bartok (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Articles about Beethoven (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Articles about Schoenberg, Shostakovich and Stockhausen (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Articles about Strauss and Wagner (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Articles about Stravinsky (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Articles about 19th century (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Brahms, Debussy, Ravel, etc.
  - Articles about 20th century (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Copland, jazz, electronic music, Hindemith, etc.
  - Articles about instruments (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Book reviews (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
  - Miscellaneous and recommendations to the library (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
- Classroom Materials, Series V; 6 Boxes
  Notebooks containing Donovan's classroom materials (lecture notes, exams, articles, etc.) comprise this section. Included in the materials for his Gregorian Chant courses are a group of letters to and from Beckett Gibbs concerning the performance practices of plainsong. Student papers are also found here.
  - Donovan's teaching notebooks
    - Composition (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
      Class notes, articles, exams, etc.
    - Counterpoint (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
    - Harmony (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
    - Theory (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
    - Orchestration (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
      Also looseleaf notebook.
    - Gregorian Chant and Plainsong (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Gregorian Chant and Plainsong (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Booklets
    - Gregorian Chant and Plainsong (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Pamphlets
    - Gibbs, Beckett, 1928-1945; 19 typed letters signed. (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Answering Donovan's questions on chant.
    - Gibbs, Beckett, postcard. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Gregorian Chant and Plainsong (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Looseleaf notebook.
    - Twentieth Century Music (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Schoenberg material and Berg material (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Stravinsky material (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Conducting (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - Rhythm sheets (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Published music used for teaching (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Mostly vocal.
    - Booklets on conducting (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Student papers - for Donovan (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Ausubel, Hillel, 1944
      Stravinsky "Symphony of Psalms".
    - Ausubel, Hillel, 1944
      Vaughan Williams Symphony in F minor.
    - Hackman, David, 1944
      Stravinsky Symphony of the Psalms.
    - Nakaseko, Kazu, no date
      Spoken Music.
    - Rosa, Gerard, no date
      Stravinsky Histoire du Soldat.
    - Rutledge, William, no date
      Berg Wozzeck.
    - Widdis, Frank, no date
      Hindemith Das Marieleben.
    - Unidentified, no date
      Wagner Die Meistersinger.
  - Student papers - for Quincy Porter (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Catuogno, Louis, 1954
      Bartok 5th Quartet
    - Gillespie, J., no date
      Berg Lyric Suite.
    - Loeffler, A.T., no date
      Bartok 5th Quartet.
    - Loeffler, A.T., no date
    - Witten, Cora Williams, no date
      Bartok 4th Quartet.
    - Witten, Cora Williams, 1954
    - Unidentified, no date
      Bartok 6th Quartet.
  - Student papers - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Robinson, Leo, no date
      Glossary of Theoretical Terms.
    - Shackford, Charles Reeve, 1954
      Intonation in Ensemble String Performance.
  - Lectures by Donovan on various subjects (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Grade books, 1944-1960; 18 items. (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Personal Effects, 1939-1970; Series VI; 1 Box
  As can be seen from the register, this is a group of very miscellaneous things found in the collection, and includes biographical material, pocket reminders, check registers, and Donovan's notebooks concerning Europe.
  - Biographical material written by Donovan for publications; awards (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Lists of Donovan's works, background information and program notes for various works, etc. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Pocket reminders, 1939-1968; 29 items. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Check registers, 5 items. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Bank statements with cancelled checks, 1968-1970; 13 items. (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Donovan's Works, 1913-1963; Series VII; 10 Boxes
  Donovan's musical works have been divided into 3 categories according to size:
  A. Octavo editions (27 cm.) Arranged alphabetically.
  B. Works 27-37 cm. Arranged alphabetically.
  C. Oversize works (larger than 37 cm.) Arranged alphabetically.
  Housed with the octavo editions are song texts Donovan collected but never used, and housed with the oversize works are unidentified sketches of music in Donovan's hand.
  To help the user, a categorical listing of Donovan's works can be found in the Index section.
  - Donovan's Works - Octavo editions - 27 cm., VII.A
    - Aye waukin O! SSA and piano., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      H.W. Gray publication, 1926
    - Beau galant, Le. TTBB and piano., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Oxford University Press publication, 1930
    - Chanson of the bells of Osenèy. SSA and piano., 4 items. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Galaxy publication, 1930
      Text (2): manuscript and typescript
      Publisher's proof.
    - Forever, O Lord. SATB and organ., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      C.F. Peters publication, 1965
    - How far is it to Bethlehem? SSA and organ., 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      H.W. Gray publication, 1927
      Arr. for TTBB and organ by Arthur Hall.
    - How great, Oh Lord, is Thy goodness. S Bar. solo, chorus SATB and organ., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Boston Music publication, 1923
    - How should I love? SSAA and piano., 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Music Press publication, 1947
      Text: typescript.
    - Jacques, come here. SSA or SSAA and piano., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Galaxy Music publication, 1952
    - Jesu, joy of man's desiring. SSAA and organ., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      E.C. Schirmer publication, 1927
    - Magnificat. TTBB and organ., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      A-R Editions publication, 1961
    - O Christ of Bethlehem. Unison, 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Holograph: 1956.
      Text: printed copy.
    - Old French and Czecho-Slovakian Christmas carols. SATB and piano., 3 items. (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Stainer & Bell; Galaxy Music publication, 1931
      No. 3. Jacques come here. Issued separately.
      Newspaper clipping: 1962
    - Part-songs, Six. SSA and piano, 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      [Oranges and lemons; Dame get up; The frog and the crow; The ploughboy in luck; There was a lady; King Arthur].
    - Poems by Eleanor Farjeon. SSAA and piano for rehearsal only., 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      E.F. Kalmus publication, 1938
      [For snow; The wind blows north; For a mocking voice].
      Text: Typescript.
    - Remember not, Lord, our offences. SSA and organ., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Savior, when night involves the skies. SATB and piano for rehearsal only., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      H.W. Gray publication, 1920
    - Sing to the Lord. T solo, chorus SATB and organ., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Boston Music publication, 1926
    - Songs of nature. SSA and piano., 2 items. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Associated Music publication, 1954
      [Dawn; Wind sings; The yellow lily; Wind of heaven].
      Text: Typescript (3 p.)
    - Subdue us through Thy kindness. TTBB and organ., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      E.C. Schirmer publication, 1928
    - Te Deum in E. SATB and organ., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      H.W. Gray publication, 1921
    - [Worship service for] Stetson University., 1 item. (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Black-line print, 1961-1962
    - Texts for songs (Box 20, Folder 6-7)
      (not used)
  - Donovan's Works - 27-37 cm., VII.B
    - Adventure. Piano solo., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Merion Music publication, 1957
      Transparencies (3 p.)
      Black-line print (2 versions)
    - Antiphon and chorale. Organ., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Black-line print copy of unrevised score.
      Page of revisions in composer's manuscript.
    - "Blow flakes, snow flakes" [Untitled song], 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      High voice and piano.
      Holograph, 1913
    - Choral preludes on American folk hymns, Two., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Music Press publication, 1948
      [Land of rest, Christian union], Organ.
      Holograph: old version of Land of rest, no date.
      Preliminary sketch of Christian Union.
    - Elizabethan lyrics, Five. Soprano and string quartet., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Text: Typescript (4 p.) and manuscript (2 p.)
      Revisions and notes concerning recording (9 p.)
      String quartet parts (4).
    - Elizabethan lyrics. Farra diddle dino; arr. Voice and piano., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Black-line print (2), 1933
    - Four songs. Selections; arr., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      Valley Music Press, c1951. (10 p. for voice and piano).
      [Away delights and Song for a dance].
      Voice and instrumental ensemble.
      Transparencies: set of parts (8 p.)
      Black-line print (2 sets of parts - 10 items).
      Notes on performance in composer's manuscript (2 p.)
    - Great Panjandrum himself, The. Monologue with piano., 4 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Holograph (2), no date
      Text: Typescript (1 p.) and composer's manuscript (1 p.)
    - "Hear my prayer, O Lord" [Untitled song]. Voice and piano., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Transparencies (2 p.), 1962
      Black-line print (2 p.)
    - Highmount. Men's voices and orchestra (or piano 4 hands)., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Sketches, no date.
    - I will sing unto the Lord. Bar. solo, chorus TTBB and organ., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Augsburg publication, 1959
      Copy of holograph.
      Sources of texts: composer's manuscript.
    - Mass. Unison chorus (optional 2 and 3 parts) and organ [with 3 trumpets and timpani in the Credo]., 6 items. (Box 21, Folder 5)
      Offset masters of organ-vocal score (15 p.)
      Offset copies (2) of organ-vocal score.
      Black-line print 3 sets of instrumental parts (36 p.), 1955
    - Paignion. Organ., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 6)
      H.W. Gray publication, 1948
    - Part-song for SSA and piano., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Holograph, no date
    - Quartet for woodwinds. Flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 7)
      Holograph score (34 p.) 1959
      Holograph set of parts (9 p. each)
    - Quartet for woodwinds. Flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 8)
      Valley Music Press publication of score and parts, 1959
      Transparencies of score (34 p.) 1959
    - Ricercare. Oboe and string orchestra., 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 9)
      Boosey & Hawkes publication of score and parts, 1944
    - Serenade. Oboe, violin, viola, violoncello., 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 9)
      New Music publication of score, 1941
      Black-line print set of parts.
      List of corrections and location of scores (3 p.)
    - [Songs]. For whom the bell tolls. Vocalise. Light the lamps up, lamplighter. Voice and piano [Vocalise for voice, violin, and viola], 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 10)
      Holograph: no date.
    - [Songs]. The minor poet. The pretty lady. The very rich man. The fisherwoman. The crusader. The actress. Voice and piano., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 10)
      Holograph score.
      Holograph voice part.
    - Taft Alma mater. Voice and piano., 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 10)
      Zimmerman Print publication, 192-
      Holograph score: 1923-1924.
    - Trumpet call for commencement, 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 10)
      Sketches (4 p.)
  - Donovan's Works - Oversize, VII.C
    - Arietta. Viola and piano., 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Holograph copy of score and part, 1942.
    - "Bingo has an enemy." Song., 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Sketches: no date.
      Text: Xerox copies.
    - Down by the Sally Gardens. SSA and Piano., 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Galaxy Music Publications (2 printings), 1931.
      Holograph, 1931.
    - Elizabethan lyrics. Now fie on love. Soprano and string quartet., 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Black-line print: 1st page of score (2), and 1st 14 measures of parts for violins and violoncello (3).
      Transparencies (2 p.): last page of score and 1st 14 measures of parts for violins and violoncello.
    - Elizabethan lyrics, five. Soprano and string quartet., 6 items. (Box 22, Folder 1a)
      1. Now fie on love!
      2. Fly hence, shadovs!
      3. The Rose.
      4. Weep eyes, break heart!
      5. Farra, diddle dino.
      Score and parts. Composers facsimile editions, c. 1957.
      Piano reduction. Composers facsimile editions, c. 1957.
    - Epos. Orchestra., 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Holograph: 2 scores, 1 dated 1964.
      Transperancy of p. 1 of original 2d movement of symphony.
      Notes and suggestions for editing (2 p.) in composer's manuscript.
    - Fable, A. Voice and piano., 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Holograph score, no date.
    - Fantasia. Solo bassoon and 7 instruments (violin, viola, violoncello, bass, celesta, timpani, percussion.), 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Black-line print copy of score and parts, rev. 1961.
    - Fantasy on American folk ballads. Men's chorus TTBB and orchestra., 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
      Holograph, no date.
      Transparencies.
      Black-line print copy of score.
      Black-line print copy of special introduction and ending for Old Bangum.
    - Fantasy on American folk ballads; arr. TTBB and piano 4 hands., 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 5)
      J. Fischer publications, 1941.
    - Fantasy on American folk ballads; arr. TTBB and piano 4 hands., 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 5)
      J. Fischer publications, 1946.
      Old Bangum.
    - Four songs. Voice and piano., 7 items. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Valley Music Press publication, 1951.
      1. Away delights!
      2. Song for a dance.
      3. O love, how thou art tired out with rhyme.
      4. Here comes a lusty wooer.
      Transparencies (10 p.), 1951.
      Black-line print score (2).
      Publisher's proof copy of score, 1951.
      Text: Typescript (2 p.) and printed copy.
    - Good ale. TTBB and piano., 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 2)
      C. Fischer publication, 1947
      Text: Typescript and printed copy.
      Information on text in composer's manuscript.
    - Homeward. Voice and piano., 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Holograph, several versions, no date.
    - Hymn to the night. SSA unaccompanied (piano for rehearsal only)., 4 items. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      J. Fischer publication, 1948
      Black-line print score.
    - Irish lullaby. Voice and piano., 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Knight of Sherwood, The. Medium voice and piano., 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Holograph, 1930
    - Lewis and Clark. Voice and piano., 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Suggestions for voice combinations in composer's manuscript.
    - Music for six. Oboe, clarinet, trumpet, violin, violoncello and piano., 2 items. (Box 28, Folder 1)
      Black-line print score and set of parts.
      Notes and suggestions for corrections (3 p.) in composer's manuscript.
    - My name shall be there. TTBB and organ., 8 items. (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
      Holograph: 2 scores, 1963; one version used for making offset masters.
      Offset masters (21 p.)
      Offset copy of score.
      Charts of rows (4 p.)
      Text: Typescript (1 p.) and manuscript copies (5 p.)
    - New England chronicle, an overture. Orchestra., 6 items. (Box 29)
      Black-line print copies of score (3); 2 with composer's emendations, 1 printed from corrected transparencies.
    - Overture in the form of a scherzo. Orchestra., 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Page's road song, A. Voice and piano., 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 7)
      Sketches (2 p.), no date.
      Text: composer's manuscript.
    - Part-songs, Three. SSATB unaccompanied (piano for rehearsal only)., 5 items. (Box 23, Folder 8)
      Indiana University Press publication, 1964
      [Lull; Vigil; Song from the second floor].
      Holograph, rev. 1964.
      Off-set masters (30 p.)
      Text: Typescript (1 p.) and manuscript copy (3 p.)
      Note on text (1 p.) in composer's manuscript.
    - Passacaglia on Vermont folk tunes. Orchestra., 5 items. (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
      Transparencies: set of parts and incomplete score, 1952.
      Black-line print, 2 scores, 1 rev. with composer's emandations.
      Notes on sources and corrections (8 p.) in composer's manuscript.
    - Piano trio, no. 1. Piano, violin, violoncello., 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Arrow Music Press, score and parts, publication, 1939
    - Piano trio, no. 2. Piano, violin, violoncello. (Box 24, Folder 4-6)
      Holograph of 3rd movement, 1963.
      Black-line print score (4).
      Black-line print 2nd and 3rd movements of score.
      Black-line print parts for violin and violoncello.
    - Sextet for wind instruments. Flute, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon and piano., 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
      Holograph: 2 copies of 1st and 3d movements, 1 copy of 2d movement.
      Holograph set of parts, 1932
      Transparencies of fragments of score.
    - Smoke and steel; symphonic poem. Orchestra, 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Holograph, 1932.
    - Smoke and steel; arr. Piano solo., 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Soundings. Trumpet, bassoon, and percussion (6 players)., 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Black-line print score (2), 1953.
      Set of parts in black-line print (xylophone, photocopy) - 7 items.
    - Soundings, rev. 1956. Trumpet, bassoon, and percussion (6 players), 4 items. (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Black-line print: 2 scores, 1 with corrections in red.
      Notes for revisions and lists of where copies of score can be found (3 p.) in composer's manuscript.
    - Suite for oboe and string orchestra., 4 items. (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
      American Composers Alliance publication (3 scores and incomplete set of parts (viola and violoncello only)), 1951.
    - Suite for piano., 4 items. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      New Music publication, 1933
      Publisher's proof (20 p.)
    - Suite for piano, no. 2., 6 items. (Box 26, Folder 4)